<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A friendly and seasonable advertisement concerning the dog-days, by Nath. Merry Philo-chim. In regard there are many that perish in and about this city &amp;c. through an evil custom, arising from a false opinion, that is not safe to take physick in the extreams of heat and cold, or in the dog days ...</title>
            <author>Merry, Nathaniel.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 3KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B26798</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99888801</idno>
  <idno type="VID">196012</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240901878</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing M1848B</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Interim Tract Supplement Guide 551.a.32[20]</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R232039</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">ocm99888801</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-99888801e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B26798)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 196012)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books; Tract supplement ; E8:2[20])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A friendly and seasonable advertisement concerning the dog-days, by Nath. Merry Philo-chim. In regard there are many that perish in and about this city &amp;c. through an evil custom, arising from a false opinion, that is not safe to take physick in the extreams of heat and cold, or in the dog days ...</title>
                  <author>Merry, Nathaniel.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([2] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1682?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Title taken from caption and first lines of text.</note>
                  <note>Imprint information from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Advertising --  Medicine --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Medicine --  Formulae, receipts, prescriptions --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="topical_term">Physicians --  England --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term type="genre_form">Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-05 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-09 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="advert_for_medicine">
            <pb facs="tcp:196012:1"/>
            <head>
               <hi>A friendly and seasonable Advertisement concerning the Dog-days, by</hi> Nath. Merry Philo-Chim.</head>
            <p>IN regard there are many that perish in and about this City, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> through an evil Custom, arising from a false Opinion, <hi>That it is not safe to take Physick in the Extreams of Heat and Cold, or in the Dog days;</hi> and some exclude Old People, Wo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>men with-child and Little Children, from the use of Medi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cine; which is as much as to say, That God hath ordained no Medicine for such Times and such Ages, which would be absurd to imagine, seeing we know there is no Time, Age, nor Disease, exempted from proper, homogenial, and eff<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>ctual Means (with Gods blessing) only against Death there is no Medicine, the time of which to us i<gap reason="illegible" resp="#keyers" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> uncertain. From the a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid Mistakes many labour under the tyranny of their Diseases, till the Catastrophe end in Death (before the time come which they have alotted for their Cure) which might by timely and suitable Remedies be prevented. It's granted
<pb facs="tcp:196012:2"/>
               <hi>pro confesso,</hi> that there is a sort of <hi>Dogmatical Medicines</hi> that is unfit to be exhibited in those times, and are not innocent at any time, being impregnated with venemous beams, which by their virulent hostility invade the Vital Oeconomy of the Body. But you may have Archeal or Vital Medicines, truly a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dapted for all times; being divested of their Crudities and He<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>terogene Qualities, by a true separation of the Pure from the Impure, and impregnated with beams of Light, which give their influence and refreshing glances upon the Vital Faculties, expels Venoms, alters Ferments; co-unites with Nature and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unites its powers to their due Oeconomy: and such Medicines being most natural and most powerful in the most deplorable Diseases, being timely taken are most effectual, and are no more to be omitted at any time than Foods; and are altogether as safe. Such Medicines I have alwayes by me faithfully prepared by my own hands. which you may have of me at reasonable rates, at the <hi>Star</hi> in <hi>Bow-lane,</hi> next door but one to the <hi>Half Moon Court.</hi> My hours are from 8 in the Morn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing till 6 in the Evening.</p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>